SUSHMA DEEGOJU

Email: sushmadeegoju16@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/sushma-deegoju-vt/ Phone: +1540-998-4213

OBJECTIVE

Passionate graduate student with 2 years of industry experience as a software engineer at Samsung and a good understanding of software development life cycles looking for full-time opportunities to leverage my technical and problem-solving skills in a company that promotes work-life balance.

SKILLS SUMMARY

Programming languages: C++, C, JavaScript, Go, Python

Web Technologies : HTML, CSS, React.js, Vue.js, Node.js, Express.js, Rest API, Figma, Material-UI

Databases : MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Others : JIRA, Gtest, SonarQube, Jenkins, Linux (proficient in Bash shell), GDB, Postman, GIT, Docker, GitLab, Visual Studio,

Android Studio, IntelliJ, Perforce, Swarm, Wireshark

EDUCATION

 Virginia Tech Blacksburg, VA

Master's in Computer Science

Aug 2022 - May 2024

Bachelor's in Computer Science

National Institute of Technology, Delhi

Delhi, India Aug 2016 - Jun 2020

EXPERIENCE

IT Security lab, Virginia Tech

Blacksburg, VA Feb 2023 - present

Web Developer

• Developed a **React.js**, **Golang**, and **PostgreSOL**-powered **Key Metrics** app, enabling 25% faster data visualization and real-time monitoring.

- Built a scalable and user-friendly VT Minimum Security Standards website using React, Go, and PostgreSQL, leading to a 30% rise in website traffic within the first quarter.
- Developed an efficient **Hugo**-powered website for IT Security Lab, achieving 50% faster page load times and improved user experience.
- · Actively involved in project planning, development, and deployment within the IT Security Lab, utilizing GitLab and Slack for seamless collaboration and communication.
- Tech Stack: React.js, Material-UI, Golang, PostgreSQL, Postman, GitLab, Slack

Samsung R&D Institute

Bangalore, India

Senior Software Engineer

Mar 2022 - Aug 2022

- Integrated a new feature into the existing QUIC protocol implementation using C++ to parse multiple crypto frames in a single TCP packet. This resulted in a 50% improvement in detecting QUIC-utilizing applications.
- Conducted thorough integration testing on **Linux-based** servers, identifying and resolving issues promptly for seamless system performance.
- Developed a Multi-layered traffic classification model using Neural Networks and achieved the accuracy of 97%.
- Led a project mentoring an intern in integrating Machine Learning frameworks into DPI for real-time algorithm performance testing.
- Tech Stack: C++, Bash, Python, Gtest, SonarQube, Jenkins, GDB, Wireshark, Perforce, Swarm, JIRA

Samsung R&D Institute

Bangalore, India

Software Engineer

Aug 2021 - Feb 2022 · Optimized the performance of Deep Packet Inspection (DPI) Engine by sending less number of bytes for detection. Implemented the code in

- C++ and received the **Spot Award** for improving the operation time by **100%**. • Automated the regression testing environment using Python scripts, improving operational efficiency by 83% and test execution speed.
- Used GDB for precise code debugging, employing breakpoints, watchpoints, and stack analysis ensuring efficient issue resolution.
- Improved the robustness of DPI solution by writing unit test cases using Gtest framework to increase the code coverage from 40% to 90%.
- Used SonarQube and Jenkins to ensure code sanity by integration testing and continuous code quality monitoring.
- Tech Stack: C++, Bash, Python, Gtest, SonarQube, Jenkins, GDB, Wireshark, Perforce, Swarm, JIRA

PROJECTS

Kev Metrics

IT Security Lab, Virginia Tech

- Developed the Key-Metrics application, designed to aggregate and visualize real-time data from diverse platforms using ServiceNow APIs.
- Developed interactive bar charts using Material-UI, enabling intuitive data exploration and visualization, leading to a 25% increase in incident prediction accuracy.
- Împroved data accessibility for IT security analysts, leading to 38% reduction in incident response time.
- Reduced data retrieval time by 40% through optimized API integration and efficient back-end processing, improving analyst workflow.
- Tech Stack: React.js, Material-UI, Golang, PostgreSQL, Postman, GitLab, Slack

VT Minimum Security Standards

IT Security Lab, Virginia Tech

- Developed a high-availability VT Security Standards website using React, Golang, and PostgreSQL, capable of handling 5,000 concurrent users with minimal latency.
- Leveraged React's virtual DOM for efficient rendering and PostgreSQL's indexing and query optimization for swift data processing.
- Implemented caching strategies for frequently accessed data, further enhancing site performance and reducing server load by 25%.
- Increased site traffic by 30% after launch, demonstrating strong user adoption and website's effectiveness in providing vital information.
- Tech Stack: React.js, Material-UI, Golang, PostgreSQL, Postman, GitLab, Slack

EasyHire (https://github.com/Sushmadeegoju/EasyHire-CareerFairPlatform)

Virginia Tech

- Implemented a dynamic career fair platform, using **React.js** for the front-end, **Node.js** for the back-end, and **MongoDB** as the database.
- Engineered a scalable and responsive platform, integrating authentication systems, real-time updates, and interactive user interfaces to optimize jobseeker-recruiter interactions.
- · Incorporated Node Mailer API within Express framework to send email notifications, enhancing the project's functionality.
- Tech Stack: React.js, Node.js, MongoDB, Express.js, JIRA, Git

CERTIFICATIONS AND AWARDS

- Spot Award for the best performance in the month of October 2020 Samsung R&D Institute, Bangalore.
- Second Runner-up at the American Express Makeathon-2019.